- Here's the mail.
- Thank you.
Um, Mr. Phillips.
- Something wrong?
- Uh, not exactly.
See, my little sister,
well, she graduates from high
school up in Richmond next Friday.
So you wanna take Friday off.
- That's all right with me, Jenny.
- Oh, heh, thank you.
Thank you so much.
Assistant Commissioner Phillips,
may I have a word with you?
- I'm sorry. Your name is?
- Carla Myers.
Councilwoman Carla Myers.
This will only take a minute.
Close the door on your way out.
Tomorrow morning at 10,
I'm holding a press conference
during which I will show
that you used this office
to embezzle close to
$100,000 in public funds.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I have proof.
Good God.
I felt it only fair to warn you.
- I was going to pay it back.
- Sure you were.
I have a son in college and
two daughters in private school.
I was temporarily short of cash.
Save it for the TV
cameras, Mr. Phillips.
Please, don't do this.
I'll resign, okay? Right
now. This afternoon.
And I'll pay back every
penny that I took. I promise.
Just don't go public with this.
You won't be just destroying
me. You'll be destroying my family.
Don't try to make me
sound like the criminal here.
This isn't about what
I did, is it? Damn it.
This is about you. And all
the publicity you're gonna get.
You're trying to make
a name for yourself.
What I did was wrong. But
what you're doing is despicable.
Well, the people are going
to think differently, Mr. Phillips.
Mm... Mm.
Pour some little hot
sauce. Just a dab.
Uh-uh, uh-uh, uh-uh,
Dad, that'll blow me up.
Uh-uh. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You'll sizzle a
little with this.
I love the taste of this.
Here. Here.
Is it gonna be too hot for me?
- Are you sure, dad?
- No, no, delicious.
- There's Arthur.
- What?
Guy who lives across
the street. Arthur.
Carla Myers accused this man,
Arthur Phillips of
embezzling close to $100,000
in the course of
his three year term
as assistant commissioner
of transportation.
Pfft. Well, there goes
the neighborhood.
Ms. Myers made the accusation
at a press conference
held this morning
at her office at
the City Council.
During my bid for election,
I promised to rid city government
of waste and corruption.
For years, grafts and payoffs
were the normal course of business.
The people of this city are victims
of dealmakers and racketeers
and I vow to bring that to an end
and I am keeping that promise.
Moreover, this is
only the beginning.
I fully intend to continue
seeking out such abuses of power.
Let's hear it for the
tumbling traffic cops.
Okay. Now it's time for
some music. A little rap music.
Yes. Cops go in for rap too.
At least, these two guys are.
Well, what do you want?
Mm.
Sorry.
That was Assistant District
Attorney Michael Brennen.
Let's hear it.
Uh, yeah. The
warrant's on its way.
Uh, uh, right. Soon
as you do, call me.
Don't you take weekends off?
Look who's talking.
Show for underprivileged
kids at the community center.
Lieutenant Davies asked
me to do my clown routine.
So, what's so important that
I had to miss my curtain call?
Carla Myers was found
dead in her home this morning.
- No. I just saw her on the news.
- Strangled. Her mother found her.
Her watch and a bunch
of other jewelry is missing.
So it may have been a
simple burglary gone south or...
Maybe it was that fella that
she accused of embezzlement.
And maybe he went bonkers.
- What was his name again?
- Arthur Phillips.
Detective Garrison's on his way
over there with a search warrant.
This one's yours, Michael,
high profile, heat from all sides.
It's right up your alley.
Make me look good.
Always do. Uh, Garrison
know to report to me?
I'll tell him when he
calls from Phillips.
So I have time to change, hmm?
- Please.
- Heh.
Yowza.
- There's Arthur.
- They're arresting him.
Yeah.
Ben, Ben. Ben,
you gotta help me.
They think I killed Carla Myers.
- In the car, please.
They found some
watch in my garage.
- Jim Gaston. Right?
- That's right.
What's going on?
The watch we found
belonged to the victim.
Her mother just ID'd it.
I don't know how
it got there. I swear.
In the car. Come
on. Watch your head.
Ben, please help me.
You did borrow his
hedge clippers last month.
Yeah. But they're old and rusty,
dull. I was gonna take them back.
No, no, no, that
ain't gonna cut it, pal.
I want him in court and I want
him on the stand. You got that?
It ain't locked.
Well, then find him, because
let me tell you something, bub,
if he's a no show, he
doesn't go on my list, you do.
You wanna be on my list?
Okay. Now, you do that.
Wonder of wonders.
It's Ben Matlock.
Michael Brennen. Pleased to
meet you. Sit down. Sit down.
- You sure this is a good time?
- Heh, public defender.
Makes him feel all self-righteous
when I yell at him like that.
- Gets him right up off his duff.
- It's an act, huh?
I hear you're something
of a showman yourself.
I don't know.
I don't have anything
like this in my office.
I love theatrical things.
They remind me that people
aren't always what they seem.
- Yeah. You from New York?
- Chicago.
- How'd you wind up here?
- I'm an old friend of Jerry Carlisle's.
When he heard about...
When he heard that I
was thinking about moving,
he suggested I come
down here and work for him.
- What'd you do up there?
- I was a defense attorney.
- Just like you.
- You know what?
I used to be an
assistant DA, just like you.
- How about that?
- Yeah. Yeah.
I understand, uh, you're
prosecuting the Arthur Phillips case.
Does that mean you're
representing him?
He's a friend, lives
across the street.
I'm always borrowing
his tools and stuff.
He never locks his garage.
Anybody could have
planted that watch there.
Yeah. Maybe.
But I'm betting that Phillips put
that watch in that tool box, Ben.
On his way from the car
to the door to the house.
It was in his path.
You hungry? I'm hungry.
You like hot dogs?
- Yeah.
- Heh, well, let's do lunch.
- You cook here?
- Yeah. Sleep in here, too, sometimes.
The bed pulls out.
How does your wife like that?
My wife's dead.
So is mine.
You know, Ben, forensics
found Phillips' fingerprints
all over the Myers house.
Are you aware of that?
Yeah. He went over there
the night before the murder
to try to talk her out of
that press conference.
- Anybody see him there?
- Well, no.
Can anybody vouch
for his whereabouts
on the day of the murder?
- Could you get that flame for me?
- Oh.
- Thanks.
- Yeah. He was in his car.
He drove around all
day and half the night
because he was too
ashamed to see anybody.
Oh, no, he wasn't,
Ben. He was mad as hell.
So he broke into her
house, strangled her,
tried to make it look like a
robbery by ransacking the house,
stealing her watch and then
he hid the watch in his garage,
intending to
dispose of it later.
Only way to chop onions. Okay.
Here's how you make your
authentic Chicago-style hot dogs.
You get your Vienna
natural casing hot dogs.
You get your Mary Anns.
- Your what?
- Your buns.
Your Mary Anns.
I have them shipped
in from Chicago.
You get your buns.
You get your onions.
But the most important
thing that you get is
your tiny hot sport peppers.
Mm. Boy, that pepper's hot.
Mm, but good.
I'll tell you the truth. That's
the best hot dog I ever had.
Heh, we're so much
alike, it's scary, Ben.
You could be my evil twin.
How many cases have you lost?
A few here and
there. How about you?
As a prosecutor? None.
Let me ask you something.
Doesn't it bother you
that Arthur's fingerprints were
found all over the scene of the crime
but none on the watch?
I mean, why would he wipe the
watch clean and nothing else?
I don't know. Maybe he
wasn't thinking straight,
because he had just
committed murder.
Brennen.
I'll be right there.
The police have been
talking to, uh, a guy
that drives a bus past Carla
Myers' house every day.
- Ah, you might wanna come with me.
- Hmm.
Now, face front again, please.
Yeah. Um...
Second guy up from
the left. That's him.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
That's the guy I saw running
out of that lady's house
the day she got murdered.
Ahem, I'm positive.
And then I saw him run around the
side of the house toward the street.
Now, why would you
remember something like that?
I mean, haven't you ever
seen a guy running before?
Not a guy his age and
not dressed like he was.
I also remember because I thought
the was gonna run out in front of me.
But he didn't.
He turned and went running down
the sidewalk in the other direction.
- And that was at what time?
- Six eighteen.
Six eighteen? Are you telling
me that at that exact moment,
you just happened
to look at your watch?
No. Of course not, I
remembered what time it was,
or about what time it was,
because I was three blocks away
from my 6:20 stop at Vine and Watson
and I was running right
on schedule, just as usual.
And you're positive
that the guy that you saw
was the guy you
picked out of the lineup.
Absolutely.
Oh, come on, Mr. White,
you're a bus driver.
Since when is having
a photographic memory
in the job description
for bus drivers?
I was robbed at
gunpoint last year
by somebody who got away with it
because I couldn't remember his face.
Believe me, since I have made it a
point to remember everybody's face
and I am sure that's who I saw.
Good.
Very good.
- Any questions, counselor?
- No.
- I think you've about hit on everything.
- Thank you, Mr. White. I'll be in touch.
Well, you don't need
my help on this one.
- Uh, you got new carpeting.
- Mm-hm, yeah.
I never got new carpeting
when this was my office.
How come you got new carpeting?
I made Griswold over
in Buildings and Grounds
a hot dog one night.
Next day, new carpeting.
- He's something, huh, Ben?
- Yeah, heh.
I'm telling you I wasn't there. He
couldn't have possibly seen me.
- All right.
- The man's lying, Ben.
Mistaken, maybe. I
don't know about lying.
What's the difference?
Because of him...
I don't have a prayer now, do I?
Don't say it. Just do
something. Please.
- Oh, hi. Heh, sorry.
- Oh.
I don't know anyone else was
here. I hope I didn't startle you.
Michael Brennen,
assistant district attorney.
Aha. I'm Leanne Mclntyre,
Ben Matlock's daughter.
- Ah.
- Heh.
- So, what are you doing here?
- I always check out the crime scene.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
Gives me a feel
for what happened,
what the killer did,
what the victim did,
how the victim must
have felt, especially that.
I never wanna forget
how the victim felt.
I know people like your
dad, they defend the accused,
guilty or innocent.
I like to think I defend
the victim, alive or dead.
I speak for her,
I fight for her.
I make sure she
doesn't get forgotten.
Although in this case, the
facts do speak for themselves.
One never knows.
I know.
Svoda, what's that?
Well, it's not in
the dictionary,
and, uh, when I called the library,
it's not Russian or French or anything.
- New restaurant?
- No. I checked with information.
There's not a
business or a store
or a restaurant of any
kind under that name.
You know, it's written so
sloppy. Maybe it's S period Voda.
My thoughts exactly.
Why don't you have a
phone book and take a look?
- Okay.
- What's in here?
That's my spaghetti sauce.
And there's already everything
in it and it won't blow me up.
Won't even make you sizzle.
- Oh, dad.
I ran into Michael Brennen
over at Carla Myers house today.
What is he doing there?
Oh, he's just getting a
feel for what happened.
I thought it was
a little strange.
So after I ran into him,
I did a little research.
His wife was killed during
a carjacking in Chicago.
- Did you know that?
- No.
The day after the funeral, he
quit his practice, moved down here,
took the bar, and started prosecuting
the bad guys with a vengeance.
Word is, he takes every
case very personally.
And he hates to lose.
- I do too.
- I just think he's gonna be tough.
- Yeah.
- What?
S v. Oda. LEANNE: Mm?
- State of Georgia v. Oda.
- The law case.
Yeah. Martin Oda.
That mobster, the one on trial for
conspiracy to commit murder last year.
Oh, yeah, that's the case where
the key witness for the prosecution,
- uh, what's his name, oh, uh...
- Uh, Frank, uh, Delong.
Delong. Right.
He disappeared from the safe
house where the feds had him stashed
before he could testify.
The state had to drop its
case and Oda went free.
But what would a city
councilwoman care about that for?
It was always rumored that
somebody in the police department
had a hand in
Delong's disappearance.
Maybe she was on the
verge of finding out who.
Maybe that's why
they killed her.
You know, there was
something else about that case.
The assistant DA who prosecuted
was so new to the job I
didn't know who he was.
- Not Michael Brennen?
- Heh.
Ain't locked.
- You got a minute?
- Sure.
I'd offer you a, uh, hot
dog. But my burner's broken.
Aw, I'm still full from
supper last night, argh.
Leanne made spaghetti.
It was okay. Didn't have
much zing to it, but it was okay.
I understand you ran
into each other yesterday.
Nice woman. Intelligent, pretty.
You must be very proud of her.
Yes, I am.
You never had any kids. Did you?
- Heh, you been checking up on me?
- Oh, no, heh. Not really.
I tell you what I have
been checking up on.
The Oda case.
Remember that case?
Of course. It was the
first one I ever prosecuted.
- You lied?
- I did?
You said you never lost a case.
Heh, it was dropped.
After we lost our star witness,
there was no longer any case to lose.
Yeah.
Did you ever figure out how
that fella Delong slipped away?
No.
But I assume your
interest in the Oda case
goes beyond catching
me in a lie. Am I right?
Well, Carla Myers, uh,
had a file on that case.
Leanne found it this morning.
She had a
transcript of the trial,
discovery hearing, the
depositions, police reports, the works.
- Any idea why?
- I thought maybe you might have one.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Well, since you prosecuted
the case, it only makes sense,
if she had a question, she'd
come to you. Don't you think?
- Well, she didn't.
- That's odd.
That's odd, unless, uh, she...
- Unless what?
- Never mind.
I don't like insinuations,
Ben. I don't like implications.
This is my office. If you
have something to say, say it.
I just wondered if she
had talked to you, that's all.
I won't take up any
more of your time.
Thanks, Michael.
Don't mention it,
heh. See you in court.
Mrs. Delong, a word
with you, please.
I'll be quick.
I told you before
and I'll tell you again.
I don't know where Frank is.
Have him give me a call.
Can't you just leave him alone?
That's Frank Delong's wife.
She owns that beauty shop.
Oh. He's angry. What
do you think he's saying?
My guess is, Mr. Brennen
wants to make sure
that Frank Delong lays very low.
Hard for me to believe
that he had anything to do
- with Delong's disappearance.
- Then what's he doing here?
Maybe a real big
fish just took our bait.
- Hello.
Hello. I'm Cliff
Lewis. I'm a lawyer.
I'm investigating the
murder of Carla Myers.
- She lived next door?
- Oh, yes, terrible thing.
- I did her yard.
- Really?
After I did this one,
and before I did that one.
- Uh, were you here last Tuesday?
- Every Tuesday.
About the same time of
day, late in the afternoon?
Sometimes very late. Yes.
Let me ask you a question.
- Well, what exactly did he say?
- Nothing. That's the whole point.
The gardener was doing the
lawn next to Carla Myers house,
and he's prepared
to testify that nobody,
not to mention Arthur Phillips,
came running out of that
house the day of the murder.
- Bus driver's lying, Jerry.
- Well, heh, somebody sure is.
And what's more, it's looking to
me like the Carla Myers murder
had something to do
with the Martin Oda case.
The Oda case?
Since Michael Brennen was
the prosecutor on that one,
we might very well be looking
at a conflict of interest here.
Uh, Michael, come upstairs for a
few minutes. Would you, please?
God help you if this is
some kind of trick, Ben.
Heh, are you serious?
Is he serious?
Are you suggesting
that I killed Carla Myers?
I'm saying your
star witness is lying
and maybe you shouldn't be
prosecuting this case. That's all.
Ben, I don't mean to be rude. But
I don't really care what you think.
Why were you with Frank
Delong's wife yesterday?
You followed me?
- You mean it's true?
- Yeah.
I talked to her.
If this is for real,
if you're really
trying to pin this murder
on me, hang it up.
If you keep shaking this tree, you're
not gonna like what falls out of it.
Just trying to keep you
abreast of the facts, Jerry.
What you do with
them is up to you.
What were you
doing out at Delong's?
That case has
always bothered me.
And after Matlock
came in yesterday
waving it in my face, it started
bothering me even more.
So I went over and
tried to get Mrs. Delong
to tell me where Frank was
and who helped him fly the coop.
Only she wouldn't talk.
Is there something you
wanna tell me, Michael?
No.
Hello, Al, 6:16 on the button.
You do run a tight ship. Don't you?
Hello, Mr. Brennen.
What are you doing here?
I'm going over to the Myers
house. I don't feel like driving.
Oh, forget it, Mr. Brennen.
Now, now, now, Al,
we city officials have to be
above reproach. Above reproach.
- Am I right, Al?
- That's right, Mr. Brennen.
Were any of these passengers
on the bus the day of the murder?
Uh, no. I don't think so.
Is something wrong?
Ah, no. Not really.
Matlock has come up
with someone who says
nobody came running out
of the Myers house at 6:18.
Don't worry about
it. I'll prove he's a liar.
Mr. White. Ben Matlock,
we met in the DA's office.
Your wife said you might
be here. How about it?
- Uh, sure. Help yourself.
- There you go.
- Tough day, huh?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. They're all tough.
- Your wife sure is in a good mood.
She's all atwitter about the
roses you got her. Three dozen.
A hundred and eighty dollars
plus tax. That's really something.
Yeah. So is my
wife. She deserves it.
- Miss? WOMAN:
Yes, sir. Just a minute.
She has no idea where
you got the money.
She figures maybe you got
some kind of bonus or something
- and forgot to tell her about it.
- Yeah. Something like that.
Michael Brennen tell
you about the gardener?
What gardener?
The one who's working in the
yard next to Carla Myers' house
the day she was murdered.
He said nobody came out of
that house, running or otherwise.
He was there the whole
time. Real good witness too.
Mr. Brennen couldn't shake
him when he took his deposition,
and believe me, he tried.
Um, service here is a joke.
I'm gonna go to the
bar, get another beer.
- Can I get you anything?
- No, no.
Ain't locked.
No need to vacuum. Just
get the waste baskets. Okay?
I don't do waste baskets.
- Burner fixed?
- Yeah. But the kitchen's closed.
Al Weiss got your phone
number in his little black book.
Excuse me?
The bus driver has this phone
number in his address book. No name.
I guess he doesn't
want people to find out
that you and he are
close personal friends.
I didn't give him
my phone number.
I saw it with my own eyes,
which pretty much confirms
what I've been
thinking all along.
Which was what?
That you paid him to lie
about seeing my client that day
so the real killer
could go free.
- I think you should leave.
- Who killed her, anyway? The mob?
For all I know, you put
that phone number in there.
Why don't you just
get the hell out of here?
Why don't you ask old Al
where he got that number?
- You can bet I will.
- You don't scare me.
I'm not trying to.
I'm saving that for Al.
That's the problem with people
who know they're committing perjury.
They scare real easy.
When I get on with old Al,
they're gonna have to get
him up off that stand with a mop.
Hmm.
It's Brennen. We need to talk.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you're about to hear evidence
that is clear and conclusive.
It will prove beyond
the shadow of a doubt
that that man over there, Arthur
Phillips, murdered Carla Myers.
His fingerprints were
found at the scene.
The watch that she always
wore was found in his garage.
A man saw him fleeing her
house at the time of the murder.
You'll also hear why Arthur
Phillips murdered Carla Myers.
You'll hear how she
as a public servant,
looking out for the public good,
that very day exposed
him as an embezzler.
You will hear how
he, his life ruined,
nothing to live for,
murdered her out of revenge,
then tried to make what he had
done look like a burglary gone awry.
That's right, ladies and gentlemen.
You will hear all these things.
And you will weigh
all these things
and they will convince you that
Arthur Phillips is guilty of murder.
The problem is, you'll be wrong.
Order. Order. Order.
Your Honor, I need to
see you in chambers.
By all means.
Mr. Matlock, you too.
This court is in recess.
Jerry. Good. Have a seat.
And when you're
good and comfortable,
you can tell me what's going on.
- What do you mean? MICHAEL:
He didn't tell me to do that.
My conscience did.
You as much as
told that jury out there
that you think the
defendant is innocent.
- What?
- On my 25 years on the bench...
this is a first for
me, Mr. Brennen.
Frankly, I'm not sure whether
I should declare a mistrial,
or slap you with a
contempt citation or both.
He's hoping for a
mistrial, Your Honor.
- Myself, I like that slapping part.
- Shut up.
Take it easy, Mr. Brennen.
What do you know about this?
I know that this case is somehow
all tangled up with the Oda case.
Mr. Brennen knows that too.
He also knows that I'm
gonna keep looking into it
as long as my client's on
trial. He doesn't want that.
- So he's throwing this trial.
- That's a lie.
Your fair-haired boy needs a
bath, Jerry. He's gotten real dirty.
All right. That's
it. You white trash.
- What did you call me?
- Nobody accuses me of being dirty.
- Dad, sit down.
- If the shoe fits, wear it and weep.
Dad. JUDGE: All right. Enough.
Everybody, sit down
and shut up. Now.
Any more outbursts like that
and I'll throw the lot of you into jail.
Okay. Where were we?
I've been looking into the
Oda case too, Your Honor,
not for any devious personal
reasons but because I want the truth.
I also feel that there is,
there's some connection
between this case and what
happened to Frank Delong
and the Oda case.
And that's the real reason
that Carla Myers was murdered.
I contacted Mrs. Delong and
she in turn contacted Frank.
He's agreed to turn
himself in to the FBI.
- When?
- Tonight.
She's going to pick him up and
drive him to FBI headquarters,
where I intend
to interrogate him
until he tells me who let
him out of that safe house.
What's the bottom
line, Mr. Brennen?
I'd like you to declare
a 48-hour recess.
He's up to something, Your Honor.
- Dad.
The truth in that case will
lead us to the truth in this case.
I'm sure of it.
Very well.
Hey, aw.
Hello, Jerry.
All right. Drop it.
Okay, Phil.
Oh, Jerry, Jerry.
You were gonna kill Frank Delong
just like you killed Carla Myers.
You'll have a hard
time proving that.
I don't know.
Now that we know that it's you,
I think the police will be able to
place you at the Myers' house.
- You agree, Bobby?
- Uh-huh.
After that, it's only a matter of time
before they can prove you're a killer.
What happened to you?
You betrayed everything
that you believed in,
the law, the
people, your office,
everything that I
thought you cared about.
Why'd you do it,
Jerry? The money?
Let's go.
The money mean that much to you?
Make sure you read
him his rights, Bobby.
I want everything by the book
so I can bury him fair and square.
Vienna natural casing hot
dogs and Mary Ann buns.
- Onions.
- Onions. How many?
This many onions.
- He cut two onions.
- Thank you, Father.
Okay. Two onions. Six dogs.
That's a third of an onion per dog.
Were they small,
medium or large onions?
I don't know. They're onions.
I hate to interrupt the
afternoon cooking show.
But I have a question about the
case. How did you know it was Carlisle?
- You didn't tell him?
- Well, I was sworn to secrecy.
I couldn't tell anybody but you.
Ben saw my phone number
in Al White's address book.
You see, up until three months
ago, my office was Jerry's,
and the phone number
was never changed.
Oh, I see.
That way you knew that he knew Al.
- Yeah.
I realized he could
have easily been the one
who snuck Delong
out of that safe house.
So I called Ben.
And we staged a scene in
Judge Caldwell's chambers
to trick him into
tipping his hand.
Now, we found his account
in the Bahamas yesterday,
three hundred and
fifty thousand big ones.
- Ooh. MATLOCK:
Come and get them.
Hold it. Don't forget these.
- Huh?
- Tiny, hot sport peppers to taste.
By the way, Michael, your
performance in the judge's chambers
the other day was
excellent. Very believable.
- Why, thank you.
- You don't think I was believable?
Well, actually, dad, you
were a little over the top.
I wasn't over the top.
It's okay, pop, you just
tend to overdo things.
Well, cheers, everybody.
Well, wait, you gotta
have a couple of these.
- They're not too hot?
- No. They won't blow you up.
www.tvsubtitles.net